[Music]
w
hello and welcome to the latest ask
abijit show I hope you're all doing
great this is episode 195 so let's see
who all is there on the live chat I can
see aush T Delta 9 Tetra Hydro
cannabinol Surendra Gupta ombe Kiker
hello K hello rakasi rajaj hello oit
mukarji rakit Mishra abav vikrant marate
the tradable
goami toan Chri
ramachandra online yo rajat Chopra hello
Aman shast mat r ainash Jimmy Kudo Dr
suryakant dager Surendra Gupta band
panda Ajay Kumar akula OAS geopolitical
dub hello vaj deshmuk Vishnu mohanan
hello J Jin 1045 maana
Alit zubon isai pritam Roy Malik T
geopolitical du again laan bagar
AR prakash paa Akash Vijay Prav harih
haran rishikesh Dash Gupta new member
hello AR lava SG Vladimir chavda
yashwant m maheswari one unar space KGB
agent prit Rahul aush Vishnu amazing
movies Clips viraj deshmuk mlin Malik
say hello Walker theorist hi Martian
aluminati Creek hello Niar bondre Cosmic
gaming Dr J Shankar Namaste Arian in
dant Monga
KR sanjoy abish sh and everybody else I
cannot greet you all individually but
hello and thank you so much for being on
this live chat on this live stream so uh
I'm going to take a bunch of questions
that you have asked in the comments I'm
going to answer those and then if there
is more time hopefully there will be
more time then we can take questions
from the live chat itself and I can see
more people joining in chra chra shakar
thi hyper NS Robin but Nanda kizor Diva
gulati johnv jwal by
learning music gaming Shivam Priyanka
javala and everybody else okay let's go
into the questions what are the
questions and what are the what do we
have from the
comments I have oh this is big from
anandu uh today in upsc prelims 2024 two
questions directly came from the ask AIT
session I was watching your videos from
the start I was keenly listening to
every word you said and curious about
your session the we you answer thank you
uh so all right before every night I try
and sleep I before I sleep I try and
watch one video of the session thank you
I really appreciate that until the
questions one was about a country of
declining population in options there
was Italy I not listen to your video
where you described about Italy I
wouldn't have had the slightest clue to
Mar the option the other question was
about op and purans and I've heard about
that too from your videos so two right
answers and yes I hope I do read your
com I did read your comment all right
thank you so much for this wonderful
comment I'm very surprised that you got
answers to questions asked in upsc
prelims from the ask abijit one of the
sessions very surprising generally you
don't get that but I'm glad it helped
you out so well thank you for the
comment I really appreciate
that okay oh wow there's three questions
here one by one is by shoit mukarji one
is by anant Pai 1154 third one is by
endan SJ has the USA reopened the Tibet
issue some us officials are coming to
India regarding this matter is the US
trying to spark a conflict between bat
and China by giving provocative
statements against China and president
she from Indian Territory why is America
suddenly why has they why have they
opened suddenly the Tibet issue if the
US frees Tibet Tibet will become a US
vasal American influence in Tibet is not
good for India is this a move to get a
military base in Tibet to counter us
shik H's speech about American plan to
create a new country a new Christian
country in India's Far East
out of Bangladesh and Burma as well has
spread all across the Indian
subcontinent is this why they're turning
to Tibet so this is an interesting
question that we have got over here and
what is the deal what are the Americans
planning so I
I somebody sent me this this image on
social media let me share it with you
all this is kind of Apt and relevant
check this out so this is kind of what
the the Americans doing are doing right
now they'll go and they'll raise the
Tibet issue and whack China's backside
with that and then they will take the TI
isue and hold put it into India's hands
and then you know then then the Chinese
get upset about the matter so
essentially what the Americans are doing
is that they are shooting off our
shoulders so you so let's say I'm India
the Americans come from the US comes
from behind they take their rifle put it
on my shoulder and fire it fire at China
from there and then when the Chinese
fire back the bullet's going to hit me
right so that's kind of what the
Americans are
doing okay so what's happened
essentially well let's understand what
has happened so uh you know that that
wonderful lady Nancy Pelosi who I think
last year went to Taiwan and really
ticked off the Chinese so she the past
week was in India she met with the with
his Holiness the Dalai Lama and she made
various statements about Tibet about
China about about Regan ping I think
being a dictator and so on so forth not
very uh nice things to say about China
obviously things that will take the
Chinese off and she made it a point to
to issue these statements from Indian
soil from
India right so obviously the CH and I'm
I'm wondering if the Chinese have resp
responded thus far to this usually they
are very quick to respond to any
American provocations but this time it's
happened from Indian
soil after or during her meeting with uh
the Dalai Lama and she referred to Tibet
she referred to the Chinese occupation
of Tibet and Sh Jinping being a dictator
and so on so forth so you know it's it's
it's very convenient for them to open
the Tibet issue where were the Americans
where was the United States
since the
1950s did they do anything about the
Chinese occupation of
Tibet initially they tried to you know
uh enlist India's help to uh counter the
Chinese occupation to I think in the
1960s I believe there was some
surveillance that was being done of the
of of the Tibetan Plateau from the himas
on on Indian in Indian Territory and uh
there was talk of of training
Tibetan uh Freedom Fighters to a little
extent and so on so there was some
something in the 1960s and then the
Americans they had this great uh you
know Raposa with the Chinese during the
Nixon kinger regime and then it was all
us Chi byby right and the Americans
conveniently forgot about the Tibet
issue I mean aren't the aren't the
Americans the champions of Human Rights
and freedom and democracy what about
Tibet what about Tibet
so all these years the Chinese have been
brutalizing Tibet the Chinese have been
destroying Tibetan culture they've been
uprooting the Tibetan language from the
region they've been settling hordes and
hordes of of Han Chinese settlers
they've reduced the native Tibetans to a
minority in their own land it's it's
cultural genocide it's it's linguistic
genocide that's happening the the
Tibetans are being replaced settler
colonialism in in action in in Tibet in
Chinese occupied Tibet and the Americans
have said not a word about these all
these decades now why is it that they
are
suddenly suddenly so so you know why
they're so interested in Tibet right now
what happened all of of a sudden so and
why are they issuing these statements
from India so they essentially want to
ensure that India and China simply
cannot have any possibility of Future
Good relations
they want to ensure that India gets
backed into a corner so that India has
no option but to be on the US side and
and India has to defer to us demands and
wishes so right now we know that there's
a war going on in Ukraine and the
Chinese are supporting the Russians
India has refused to condemn the Russian
actions and and the Russian
invasion and russan Ria is definitely
facing the prospect of
becoming too much indebted to China
essentially becoming a Chinese vasal
Russia is more powerful militarily but
China is way more powerful economically
Russia could end up becoming an economic
vasal of China and India is crucial in
this matter to kind of offset
that
but the Chinese would not want want
India to get involved too much so there
there complicated situation over here
and from the US perspective India has
very limited utility they don't want to
see India grow as a as as a mighty
economic power they want to see India
constrained and confined and and and
limited to where it is today
economically and they would like to use
India as a counterweight to China the
ideal situation for the US is that India
and China go to war and Bash each
other's brains out that's it both
civilizations are smashed up and the
Americans can then peacefully deal with
Russia at their
Leisure so that is a nightmare scenario
for Russia as
well
so the problem when it comes to the
India China relationship is the Chinese
actions the Chinese have been the
belligerant party they started the the
various Wars that happened 1962
1967 1987 I believe there was a limited
clashes and all that the the Chinese
have been the provocators they are the
ones who have steadfastly refused to
demarcate the Border and so on so forth
the Americans want to take advantage of
that they want to paint India into a
corner they want to push India into
position where India has no option but
to exceed to the US demands and
hopefully India can then cut off its
ties with Russia as well eventually
that's what the Americans would want so
they are ensuring that they they
infuriate the Chinese and drag India
into the picture so the Americans don't
care about Tibet understand this very
well the Americans if they cared about
Tibet they would have done something
about this a long long long time ago
they would not have cooperated with
China and aided and Abed in Midwife
China's rise since the 1970s ' 80s
onwards the Americans don't care about
Tibet it's simply a
convenient like I like I showed that
image it's simply a convenient stick to
beat the Chinese with and to and to drag
India into the process this here Tibet
is simply a convenient tool for the US
to create problems between India and
China they simply do not care about
Tibet they don't care if the if the
Tibetans exist or or if they seize to
exist it is simply a cynical
geopolitical Ploy and a very crude one
at that so uh I so why did India allow
this so first of all India cannot say no
to Nancy Pelosi India cannot deny a visa
to Nancy Pelosi that would be tantamount
to a hostile
action relations between the between the
US and India are reasonably okay right
now despite all the things the US is
doing you know accusing Indians various
Indian people of trying to assassinate a
terrorist a US sheltered Terrorist on us
soil and so on so the Americans are
provoking India they they're Sheltering
various anti-india elements they are
still supporting Pakistan in a variety
of ways they are you know pressing
placing all kinds of pressures on India
but they want India to cooperate with
them that's the way that's the way this
superpower deals with other nations uh
so India cannot refuse a v visa to Nancy
Pelosi and India cannot tell her what to
say what not to say the US is too
powerful a nation for us India to
dictate to them what they can speak and
what they cannot speak and we are simply
not powerful enough right now India is
from a hard power perspective the fourth
most powerful nation in the world but
compared to China India is about a third
or a fourth of China's power China is
about a fourth of Russia's power and
Russia is about half of the US power
hard power the US is is 20 times more
powerful at least compared to India more
than that perhaps so India is no match
for the US and India has to keep its
head down and India cannot say India
cannot dictate things to the US you can
negotiate and so on so forth but certain
things you can't do so the Americans
will use that power to come and ride
rough sh over India and create all these
issues and there's not much India can do
right now because you don't understand
what the Americans are capable of off
they can devastate a nation if they want
to so it's it's a very danger it's like
it's like playing with a bear or playing
with a
dragon and the bear is Russia the dragon
is China and imagine something way more
powerful than the bear of the Dragon
that's the us so you got to be very
careful about that so the Americans are
trying to create problems between India
and China they want to ensure that there
is no rosma between India and China in
the future which is the nightmare
scenario for the for the US imagine if
somehow somehow I don't know how but
imagine if India and China are able to
set their differences aside at least for
a decade and work together I'm not
saying it's going to happen but imagine
this almost impossible scenario then
India China and
Russia can actually work together with
other like-minded nations that that is a
genuine genuine big problem for the us
if that happens so the worst case
scenario for the US is India and China
putting aside their differences and
cooperating that would be the worst case
disaster for the US the best case
scenario for the US is India and China
going to war and killing each
other so which scenario what the US
prefer obviously they would like to
create problems between India and China
and that's what the Americans are doing
so they're not doing this out of any
Love For Freedom democracy human rights
blah blah blah they're not doing this
out of any love for the Tibetans they
don't care that the Tibetans live or die
they are doing this out of cynical
self-interest understand that
flower
6637 says after the announcement of the
new nalanda University I have seen some
extremist Buddhists trying to claim it's
so funny that Buddhists can be
extremists Buddhism bodha Dharma is a
religion of I mean a
genuine a genuine religion of Peace
isn't it but now and and and you know
the the peaceful religions the genuinely
peaceful religions are the dharmic
religions Hinduism Buddhism jism more or
less did I miss something I'm sure I did
not okay do a I do apologize if I miss
something now um so when imagine Janes
being extremist what what would an
extremist Jan look like an extremely
extremist Jane would be the most
nonviolent person you can imagine
extreme extremities of nonviolence the
asymptotic uh solution when it comes to
solving
nonviolence that's what an extremist
Jane would look like an extremist
Buddhist would also be something like
that but today we have extremist
Buddhist so when we're talking about
these so-called extremist Buddhist
understand that we are talking about
political uh activists okay this is all
politically motivated now so she's
saying that she has seen some extremist
Buddhists trying to claim credit of the
ancient nalanda University by calling it
a Buddhist University why is that so
first was Nanda University a Buddhist
University or as much as I know it was
founded created by a Hindu Dynasty and
secondly some of these extremist
Buddhists even try to claim that
Buddhism is older than Hinduism is that
so okay so look you know lots of people
today for some reason believe that
Buddhism is older than Hinduism and
Nanda was a Buddhist University Etc and
you know these people are not bad people
please understand that if somebody has
views that are different from yours or
opposite of yours it doesn't mean they
are bad people it means they genuinely
believe it is
true if people watch certain content
creators and believe them it it doesn't
mean they're bad people the ones who
watch it means that they believe these
people are are doing something good for
the country and they saying something
for the for the country's betterment so
they genuinely actually most likely we
to understand we to give people the
benefit of the doubt that they may
actually want to they may seek something
good for the country and they may be on
the wrong
path now the question is when a regular
ordinary Indian wants to find
information seek information where do
they go they go to Wikipedia correct and
let me once again reiterate that
Wikipedia is an extremely unreliable
source of information okay but let's see
what it looks like from their
perspective shall we nalanda University
so let's go to let's go to Google and do
a Google search for Nanda University and
see what Wikipedia has to say because
I'm sure Wikipedia will be the first uh
search result that turns up
okay nalanda
University
now what does it tell us it it gives you
this new University right but uh yeah
okay so so when you search for Nanda it
turns up this search result Wikipedia
and in Wikipedia it's not called nalanda
University is called nalanda mahavihara
let's look at the history of this uh
Wikipedia entry let's go to 500 the last
500 uh
revisions and let's see what it looked
like on on the first of January 2024
because lots of revisions keep happening
okay 6th of January let's
see it was still saying Nanda mahavir
vihara over here it says it was a
renowned mahavar in ancient magad okay
it was it doesn't say Buddhist
University but in the current the
current re version it says Buddhist
mahavar or something like that let's go
to 2022 so you can see that people have
been editing this so many edits in 2023
and every year let's go to the end of
2022 okay let's see the last edit of
2022 what's it
say uh nalanda mahavihara it says it was
a renowned mahavihara into brackets
Buddhist monastic
University you can see there are
hundreds of r Visions every year now
let's go and see what it says right now
so it says it was a renowned Buddhist
mahavar okay so that's why people will
believe that nalanda was a Buddhist
University because they will first of
all go to Wikipedia because their
teachers and their education system will
not teach it will will give them very
little information if at all anything
about mahavira maybe about nalanda maybe
a paragraph or two so what's it
say now the question uh that uh I'm
sorry the question that has been asked
here is was it a Buddhist
University so let's see so it's possible
that nalanda was is more than 3,000
years old it's possible but as far as we
know the official uh mainstream history
version narrative or or whatever you
want to call it is that it was founded
during the Gupta era of India the Gupta
dynasty the Gupta Empire probably
kumaragupta let's see what it says early
history of the C of city of Nanda that's
okay what is the official version of the
founding nanda's datable history be
begins in the fifth
century uh blah blah
blah okay what else what else what else
um okay so kumara Gupta one was the
founder patron of the nalanda monastery
University okay numismatic evidence etc
etc corroborates that Kumar Gupta one
was the founder Patron so kumaragupta
was a was an emperor of India an emperor
of the Gupta dynasty his Reign his his
rule was during the roughly roughly the
first half of the fifth century ad okay
now understand that the Gupta Empire
Gupta dynasty was a Hindu Dynasty first
of all we have to understand that this
difference between Hinduism Buddhism is
something that is that has been created
in the past Century or so historically
the it was bodha Dharma was one of the
dharmic puns one of the philosophical
schools of thought of Dharma
just like s Naya vasik Vidant so on so
forth J and etc etc staraka and much
more one of the valid legitimate Paths
of Hindu of of
Dharma but the westerners created a
division and now we see Buddhism as a
separate
religion Buddhism bodha Dharma is is is
is the same thing as any other Dharma
but there are subtle
differences but if you want to consider
bod Dharma as a separate religion why is
charaka not a separate religion why is
mimansa not a separate religion why is
Yoga nashik not separate religions why
is vant not a separate religion now that
I'm saying that they will try and do
that as well so first of all understand
that bodha Dharma is not some separate
religion it is nothing but one of the
dharmic puns one of the dhic paths and
if you want to see it as SE as a
separate path then you have to
acknowledge that the go Gupta Empire
Gupta dynasty was a Hindu Dynasty and
not not a dynasty that followed the
bodha dharmic path okay kumaragupta was
a Hindu emperor not a Buddhist Emperor
understand that now let's go back to
this Wikipedia
page so kumaragupta one the founder was
not Buddhist first of all okay the
founder Patron this is the official
history of of nalanda as per the
so-called mainstream historians uh um
and many donors were not Buddhist once
again their emblems on their seals show
lakmi Ganesh shivling and Durga there
you go so the the during the foundation
of the University as per official
history you the founder was a Hindu and
many of the seals of the donors have
lakmi Ganesh shivling Durga etc etc
etc uh rurals in rulers in rulers in
Northeast India be villages to fund
Alanda the king of Sumatra contributed
Villages for the monasteries endowment
and so on so forth special fund was
established to support Scholars from
China so every nation would fund its
Scholars Etc China Korea Etc you have
Schwan Zang from China very very famous
monk who came to India Schwan Zang over
here now what else do we know Korea
Tibet it's Tibet was a free independent
nation I mean culture at the time not
under Tibet not under under China then
you have the paa Dynasty and so
on now what is interesting about the par
Dynasty okay check it out an endowment
by the shendra king balra of swad DEA
which is suad which is Sumatra in
present day Indonesia okay he was a king
of swad of of Shri Vijaya his name was
balra DEA he was the Maharaj of Shri
Vijay in the 9th century ad and he had
built a monastery there and by the way
he was a Hindu okay swabi swad via was a
Hindu Kingdom the entirety of Indonesia
was a Hindu Empire okay so Hindus were
donating and building monasteries and
giving grants and Villages giving the
granting the revenue of villages to up
for the upkeep of nalanda and so on then
you have the gosan inscription which is
another inscription from dapa's time it
mentions that he received and patronized
a bshu called V DEA who had studied all
the vas in his youth all the vas in his
Youth and who was later elected as the
head of nalanda so the head of nalanda
was a gentleman who had studied all the
vas so do you see the history this is
the official Wikipedia
history you get it so where's the
Buddhist angle in
this the founder according to the
official version of History was an
Indian Hindu Emperor many of the donors
most of the donors as is written
demonstrated in Wikipedia
where Hindus you can see seals and
inscriptions of lakmi and Durga and
shivlingas and Ganesh etc etc etc there
is the there is there is not Buddhist
there is Hindu then you have various uh
Kings Hindu Kings of Indonesia and other
places who are donating all kinds of
stuff to to Nanda building monasteries
there and so on so you can see where
where is the Buddhist angle in this now
it's being called Buddhist mahavihara
and by the same Wikipedia page by the
way what is that cognitive
dissonance so all right so I think that
should settle it from the Wikipedia page
itself even though it's not entirely
reliable I would caution you again so I
I just don't understand why people can't
think think at least at least spend some
time and read what they what what's
written there don't just read the first
paragraph of the first line of the first
paragraph spend some time right please
please I know it it hurts I know it's
hard thinking and reading is hard I know
but do some hard work it'll help you in
life now the second question some of
these extremist Buddhists even try to
claim that Buddhism is older than
Hinduism is that so okay tell me
something in which Buddhist
text is there a mention of a physical
description of the
sarasti the sarasti the physical River
it existed there is no question question
about its existence today it's been
demonstrated it's been
proven many papers have been written
about it in nature itself the world's
most prestigious scientific journal so
there's no question about the fact that
the sarasti existed and that River dried
out
mostly uh in in roughly about 1500 BC
around that time okay it did not dry out
entirely it still exists in Northern
India it is called the gagar and it's
still floods in the in the in the Rainy
during the Rainy seasons and it still
looks like the mother of floods so the
sarasti did exist some of it still
exists all the way up north in India
harana
Etc so the Saraswati did exist no
question about it show me one Buddhist
text that has a physical description of
the Saraswati by an eyewitness or
somebody who traveled any Buddhist biku
monk Etc
whoever who witnessed the sarasvati with
his or her own eyes is there a single
description in any Buddhist
text I can I can give you Hindu
texts that have voluminous copious
physical descriptions of the
sarasti mother of floods loudly Roaring
River and so on so forth the rig way
that the oldest known literature is in
the history of humankind it has
copious descriptions of the
sarasti and this River mostly
disappeared around 3 and a half thousand
years before today and the rig wether
describes the river in its prime when it
was a gigantic scary River and also the
mother of a civilization and you know
Saraswati is the goddess of wisdom and
and knowledge right we still rever her
today at least some of some of those
some of do the Japanese Reve her in the
form of benan
so tell me which Buddhist text has a
physical description of the sarasti I
assure you there's none whatsoever but
the
Riga has description of the sarasti
damayan has description of the Saraswati
even the Mahabharat has description of
the sarasti but in the Mahabharat the
sarasti is on the in the process of
drying out so what does that tell you
what what comes first Buddhism or
Hinduism
my point is why are we creating these
artificial differences B the DH is
nothing but one of the dharmic
paths okay it's different in some ways
some small subtle ways from the other
dhic paths like all the dharmic parts
are different from each other in subtle
ways whether it is both whether it is
Naya whether it is Jina whether it's
mimansa charaka
yoga what vidanta and so on so forth
right they're all different in some ways
it doesn't mean they're separate
religions but these foreigners these
Outsiders have created these artificial
divisions and we are fighting on the
basis of this
nonsense but my point is B the DH came
way
later it it when
did when did goam Buddha live about two
and a half roughly two and a half
thousand years before today roughly
okay uh so it's it's very clear I mean
there's no question what comes first
Buddhism all of them Hinduism I don't
know what where these people come from
just don't understand anyhow I hope that
answers the
question next
question okay let's have the next
question all right there here we are
it's by Rod sarar other than the cholas
did any other Indian Dynasty attack and
Conquer parts of Southeast Asia uh as
far as we know there is no other Dynasty
Indian Dynasty that attacked invaded and
conquered militarily any parts of
Southeast Asia the chers were the only
one that did that
roughly a thousand years before
today approximately A Thousand Years
give take maybe two three years almost A
Thousand Years the anniversary of the
cha conquest of Sir Vijaya so let's go
to the map I mean we haven't gone to the
map today what am I doing I'm I'm losing
my touch okay let's see the
map what was this Conquest all about so
here we are we can see the Indian
continent you can see the uh Indian
Ocean the Sea of sashtra the Sea of
Kalinga Kalinga sea then you have the
uh um the chasi over
here and you have SRI Vijaya over here
which is now called Sumatra okay this
island
here this is Sumatra it was historically
called SRI Vijaya and then you have Yad
over here the island in which you have
Jakarta bandong suraya Etc and so on
then you have Bali etc etc etc so so
here's the deal the cholas were the
major uh Empire in the southern part of
India and uh I believe rajendra Chola
the son of rajar Raj had was a great
conqueror he had even conquered Kashi I
mean um
Varanasi I believe uh if I'm not
mistaken and he had his Dominion
extended itself to Sri Lanka and be
Myanmar
Etc now the deal and and SRI Vijaya was
his wasal okay it was his wasal and they
acknowledged his suity the suty of the
Chola Empire but uh it was a wasal in
name which means that they paid some
Tribute every year some tax every year
and that was it but they were otherwise
independent now here is the
thing uh the SRI vij rulers where they
had diplomatic IC contacts with the
Chinese and to the Chinese it is said
that they were representing themselves
as the overlords of the Chas they were
saying to the Chinese that the Chulas
are our
wasal when actually they were the wasal
of the
Chas
okay uh so that I believe was the the
just cause let's say for the cholas for
rajendra Chola to launch his invasion of
Sri Vijaya of course there are other
reasons more more material reasons for
doing this you can uh control the trade
which passes through the malaka strait
the malaka strait is a vital choke point
even today this here is the malaka
Strait the straight of
malaka uh and and it's a strategic choke
point that the Indian uh Navy dominates
so all the trade with southeast Asia
with China Etc still even a thousand
years ago passed through the through the
malaka State and uh the SRI VI Vijaya
Kingdom had complete control over that
and they could tax anybody who passed
through that and some of the revenues
went to the Chas but why not all of the
revenues right so there was that and and
this region SRI via uh was extremely uh
rich in various kinds of resources
spices Etc so why not control all that
so these were some of the reasons and
obviously if you can if you conquer this
gigantic Island it obviously adds to
your Pres in your military press and
your power projection and so much more
it's all geopolitics yesterday I mean
what we call history today when it was
happening was geopolitics okay so for
these geopolitical reasons the cholas
they used this as a pretext that the S
vians were representing themselves as
the overlords of the cholas to the
Chinese so they said okay let's teach
you a lesson so so the
cholas uh they invade SRI via they
conquer s via and they take over the
whole place and it's it's
essentially a regime change
operation and they Place their own PE
their own puppet King in place but
understand this the Chas did not carry
out massacr in Sri via the Chas did not
destroy infrastructure cities Villages
Etc in Sri via the Chulas did not
plunder any wealth out of Sri Vijaya the
Chas did not impose a foreign religion
on SRI via it was the same religion by
the way so the Chas were shites and SRI
Vijaya was whatever so no big deal there
but all they did was they extended their
power projection capabilities and
eventually they conquered they they
established the they extended their
Imperial Outreach all the way to the
Philippines that's what the Chulas did
and and S SRI Vijaya was a stepping
stone towards that so so that is what
happened and that is why the cholas
invaded that is why rajendra Chola
invaded SRI vij and conquered it
uh apart from that I don't know of any
other Indian Dynasty that
militarily conquered or even attacked
any other part of Southeast Asia all the
other indianization that happened in
Southeast Asia was entirely through
trade and cultural uh
contacts so there was no uh forcible
conversions or military conquest that
was the vector that um propagated Indian
culture religion all of that happened
not because of the Chulas but actually
because of the people of Kalinga who
were trading with swabi southeast Asia
Etc more than 3,000 years before today
so over time the whole of Southeast Asia
became indianized and you had all these
Hindu kingdoms all across southeast Asia
all the way to the Philippines and today
the Philippines the people of the
Philippines don't even know that their
ancestors were Hindus that they had
rajas in the Philippines at least the
people of Indonesia do remember and they
in Indonesia and in Indonesia the Hindu
period of Indonesia is recognized as the
greatest as the Golden Age of Indonesia
the majapahit Empire anyhow that's the
answer okay
we we WEAU says why did the chagatai
khet the ilh in the golden horde adopt
Islam as the state religion of their
Empires and why did they abandon
Buddhism M after initially adopting it
okay is good question so these Empires
that you're talking about the chagatai
khet the ilhan the garden horde Etc were
successor states of the great Mongol
Empire the golden horde if I remember
correctly was founded by Batu no no no
who was it wasn't it wasn't B it was ji
I believe Joi Joi was the firstborn son
let's say of chingis Khan there there
are still question marks about his
paternity and we will never have the
answer to that long story I'll not go
into that but yes these were all
successor states of the Mongol Empire
founded by the great conqueror and
Warrior for peace Shri chingis Khan okay
I know it pisses off a lot of people
that's why I say
that okay now so the Empire became so
large that without modern
telecommunications you simply could not
control and coordinate things and that's
why it had to break up and then chingis
Khan's son took over various parts of
the Empire so that's how you have the
golden horde the chak khet the khet and
so on so forth and all these Empires the
successor states were based in Central
Asia and Western Central Asia let's go
to the map once again of course we have
to
so this region the STS you know so
Mongolia of course if if you let's say
you're in Manipur you have to just go
straight North straight North straight
North and if you go about about let's
say 2,000 km 2,300 kilm he will end up
in Mongolia okay straight North from
Manipur let's say so that is Mongolia
and west of Mongolia there were these
enormous territories that were conquered
by first of all Shar chingis Khan and
then by his son OG Khan and then other
his other descendants so there was a
gigantic Mongol Empire it eventually had
to break up for logistical reasons and
these successor states were based in
Central Asia
and Western Central Asia and even parts
of Eastern Europe Etc and obviously the
Caucasus region
and uh
turkistan etc etc now the the point is
this so the Mongol Empire was a Buddhist
was initially a tarist Empire the
religion of sh chingis Khan was tengrism
what they call tengrism it is a
polytheistic religion not a monotheistic
religion as lots of people try to claim
it's a polytheistic religion the sky
father thri the Earth Mother umay Forest
Spirits the spirits of your ancestors
and much more you call that monotheism
seriously are you kidding me
polytheistic
so first of all it was the thing the
official religion was theism let's call
it theism then because of the influence
of Tibet and India and so on and and
China as well China was entirely
Buddhist I mean significantly Buddhist
so then Buddhism became kind of the de
facto official Major majority mainstream
religion of the Mongol Empire after the
demise of Shri chingis Khan for example
during the time of
Shri Kuai Kuai Khan the Yuan emperor of
China the defacto state religion was
Buddhism in China um in the Mongol
Empire the Mongol Empire part of China
which was entirely China right so
Buddhism was the official or or DEA
facto religion of the overall Mongol
Empire then you have these kets that
that split out of the Mongol Empire and
they are based mainly in Central Asia
and Western Asia and over there that's
all turkic regions the Turks had wiped
out the skians by this time okay by the
12th 13th century ad and the all all of
this entire vast step region of Central
Asia Etc was all turkic and all Islamic
by that time so you have Mongols ruling
over an entirely almost entirely Islamic
population and then there'll be
intermarriage and all that so over time
it just happened see the thing is this
polytheists are very adaptable they will
very
quickly ad you know by a process of
osmosis or whatever adopt the local
Customs but once you become monotheist
it it the other thing the other way
around doesn't happen because polytheism
is very very pluralistic and accepting
and open-minded while monotheism is is
not that way so because of intermarriage
because all their subjects were Muslims
and so on I think it just happened over
time that the the the rulers the Mongols
became turkified and they intermarried
and they they themselves became Muslims
and that way they were able to control
the population better identify the with
the population better uh the were able
to exert more influence on the officials
and the the lower aristocracy nobility
whatever you want to call it and that's
what
happened so that that's how the Mongols
the the chat khh the golden H Etc they
became turkified and
islamized uh yeah so that's how it went
and eventually they they just became
turkic they just became
turkic that's how it went
Malik Sayad says I'm able to see a
pattern in Russia that demographics are
changing very rapidly like there are
many there's a lot of conversion
happening to Islam I heard that this is
what the Islamic world is doing to
counter the Jewish presence in the US
and they've started to capture a core
position inside Russia do you think in
the future it'll be a USA versus Russia
thing more like Jewish versus Muslim
also some estimates show that Russia
will be an Islamic country by the 2050s
if this is not controlled also can we
see Russia standing with the Arab world
on majority issues where do you see this
going
okay interesting question interesting
question so let's look at the
demographics religious demographics of
Russia let's go to a Google yes let's go
to Google and let's see what the
official thing is what are the
demographic of Russia right right now so
we're going to take the help of
Google okay
religious
demographics of
Russia let us see what it says we don't
go to the going to go to the Department
of State not interested we'll go to
Wikipedia I think Wikipedia is more
reliable than than the US Department of
State so let's say what Wikipedia has to
say um this is what 2012 no let's see
more something more recent 2024 religion
in Russia 2024 okay this is not entirely
100% accurate or reliable not
necessarily but let's take it as a rough
indicator of the religious demographics
so in 24 61.8% of Orthodox Christianity
2.6% other Christianity that is
64.4% Christianity okay let's say 64%
Christianity 99.5%
Islam
21.2% no religion and then there are
other religions in Undeclared the other
religions would include let's say what
Buddhism maybe a little bit of shamanism
Hinduism there is some Hinduism that's
emerging and Eastern religions
neopaganism whatever but we're talking
about uh Christianity and Islam over
here mainly so no religion is 21%
Christianity is 64 or so perc and Islam
is 99.5% okay and if you look at uh so
that's the religious demographics now
let's look at a map once again of Russia
and let's understand where what
exists so if you look at Russia it's
this big country up north and the
western part is all let's say mostly
Orthodox Christian then you have the
Caucasus region where you have
Christianity uh sorry Islam in Chia in
dagistan
mainly uh so that's where you will have
uh significant Islamic populations and
then you have the Tatar people who are
spread all across the uh Siberian region
not the Siberian region but the pre
Siberian region let's say of of Russia
so the the Tatar people significant
percentage of these people would be
Muslims there are lots of famous tatars
like the tennis playing siblings Dinara
and uh Marat Dinara Safina Marat safin
those were those two are tatars and many
more tatars are there in Russia and then
so that's the kind of thing you have so
the overall percentage of Muslims in
Russia is right now
99.5% so do we see Russia becoming an
Islamic country by the 2050s I think
even if the Islamic population has way
more children than
the non-islamic population in Russia at
9.5% right now and in 26 years I don't
think they'll become a majority
demographically so I don't think Russia
will become majority Islamic by the
2050s or maybe even by 2100 unless there
is an active conversion not just new
births but active conversions of other
religions Etc to Islam not sure if it's
that hap if if it's really happening I
have personally not seen any news of
that maybe I I may not be looking in the
right places or maybe I not may not be
looking at all actually right uh but I
don't see that happening right now I
mean uh compare Russia with India uh I
don't know what the Islamic population
of India is right now in 20 the 2011
census what was it 14% 16% something
like that by now it may be 20% or more
if you include the the Bangladesh's who
are illegally in India maybe 20 plus %
of of India may be Muslim so I would say
India has a much larger chance of
becoming an Islamic country by 2050 than
than Russia for sure so I don't think
Russia is gonna become a Muslim country
anytime soon but I'm not saying it may
not happen maybe by 20100 it may become
a Muslim Muslim country POS possible
perhaps who knows uh now the Islamic
world is doing this to counter Jewish
presence in the US well if you look at
the Jewish demographics in the US I
think it's less than 1%
so uh but I know what people claim some
people claim I'm not claiming this okay
I'm not saying anything about it but
some people claim that the Jew the
Jewish Lobby in the US is very
influential and they control everything
that's that's what they claim uh do we
have any evidence of that well I don't
know I'm not really looking into it
let's
say okay uh so does it mean the US is is
a essentially a Jewish country I I don't
think so I don't think so yeah Israel is
and Israel obviously has
its number one Ally is the US and the US
uh has generally supported Israel
unconditionally in everything um and
Russia has been standing with Palestine
Russia has been standing with everything
uh that the Americans are are against so
it's because of the situation right now
the Russians did not want this war with
against NATO and all but they've been
pushed into that that's how it is uh so
yeah the Russians are standing with
Palestine the Russians have kind of an
alliance with Iran with with Syria Syria
exists as an independent country because
of Russia right now otherwise the
Americans would have done a regime
change in the early 2010s the Russians
prevented
that so Russia is ensuring that there is
a certain balance of power in various
parts of the world including in the
Middle East so that's how I see it uh
Russia has its own interests uh I don't
see it becoming a Muslim country anytime
soon maybe by 21 100 if things go in a
certain direction it may happen but not
by 2050 for
sure okay Vishal Kumar says why is China
claiming the territories of arunachal
Pradesh have they ever ruled any parts
of arunachal okay good question let's go
to the
map so in case some of my viewers don't
know what we are talking about we're
talking about arunachal Pradesh which is
a state in the Far East of India in the
northern part of the Indian Far East and
most Indians will call it the northeast
of India which is a ridiculous term
because it's not in the North or in the
it's Far East just like Kamchatka Etc is
the Far East of
Russia you know Kamchatka sakhalin this
is the island of sakal this is the
Kamchatka pinula that's and all that
that is the Far East of Russia similarly
Arun Nel nagaland Manipur Assam all that
all that is the Far East of India my
dear friends now I'm sure people will
start catching on and soon you will have
YouTubers saying Far East Far but right
now it's me who saying it so the point
is arunachal Pradesh is this big uh
State over here it's in the foothills of
the Himalayas it's a kind of a Himalayan
State it's very
forested and the Chinese claim this
state as their territory essentially in
its entirety now what's the history
what's the history have the Chinese ever
ruled over arunachal the Chinese have
never ever ruled over arunachal so
what's the basis of their claim over
arunachal well the Chinese say that they
claim Tibet because of historical
reasons and they said that Tibet had
some some sovereignty over some parts of
arunachal in the past which means that
arunachal is is Chinese and they call it
what zangan or some stupid ridiculous
name like that the Chinese are our
masters are being ridiculous actually so
that is Now Now understand what okay if
if you want to understand the real
history H let's let's quickly delve into
that you see the Great Mongol conqueror
it it starts it goes back to Mongolia if
you want to understand China's claim on
arunachal you have to go back to the
12th and 13 centuries to understand
because you have to go back in time to
see the root causes you understand so
sit back relax and let me tell you a
story in the early 13th century the
great Mongol conqueror Shri chingis Khan
decided to avenge centuries of Chinese
atrocities on the people of Mongolia by
conquering
China so he crossed the GOI desert it
was extremely dangerous extremely
difficult but he did that and
he uh conquered various parts of China
they submitted to
him uh and then he went westwards
conquered karazma for various reasons
I'll not go into that if you want to
understand you can see my video on that
and then the Chinese rebelled to make a
very long complicated story short the
Chinese rebelled so chingis Khan went
back to China and he he smashed Beijing
he flattened Beijing he conquered most
of China and then he died in the process
and then he ordered his brother and his
sons to complete the conquest of China
and then his third son ogai was
appointed the next great
Khan by chinis himself before he died
long before he died he had he had made
it very clear who's going to be the
successor so ogai becomes the next Khan
and he completes the conquest of China
and then one of China chingis Khan's
grandsons Shri kubl Khan becomes the
Emperor of China and he's a Mongol and
he establishes what the Chinese call a
conquest Dynasty called the Yuan Dynasty
and then the Yuan Dynasty Emperors
retrospectively date back and say that
the first Yuan Emperor was Shri chungis
Khan okay so the Yuan Dynasty rules
China for a for a certain period of time
and the Chinese now say it was a Chinese
dynasty even though it was a Mongol
Dynasty that was occupying and ruling
China now the Yuan Dynasty under Shri
kubl Khan it had a guru shisha
relationship with
Tibet so Tibet was the guru and Mongolia
and the Yuan dynasty was the shisha or
the or the pupil okay and Tibet was the
guru in terms of spirituality and and
and culture and religion
Buddhism so um
the Yuan Emperors would have Tibetan
Monks in their court and they would
teach them Buddhism and they would you
know take care of religious Affairs
across the Empire and the the Yuan
Dynasty the Yuan Empire would in return
offer protection to
Tibet they did not militarily occupy
Tibet they did not force Tibet to pay
any tribute to to the Yuan Empire but
Tibet was a protectorate of the Yuan
Empire okay just like Bhutan is a
protector kind of a protectorate of
India today so Tibet was not a vasal of
the Mongols it was a
protectorate but the Chinese claim now
today okay they they invent all kinds of
wonderful convenient excuses today the
Chinese Communist party so the Chinese
Communist Party says that the Yuan
Empire was a TI was a Chinese Empire and
they claimed that Shri kubl Khan was a
Chinese emperor and then they claim that
was a wasal of the Yuan Empire the
Chinese Yuan Empire which automatically
gives China a legitimate claim over
Tibet so they conquered Tibet because
the great magnificent Shri Neu G allowed
them to do that and actually helped them
to conquer Tibet in the 1950s and then
they Justified the Chinese then
Justified their their occupation of
Tibet by cracking out this old map and
and spinning this fabulous Fantastical
tale so so they claim Tibet on on the
basis of this of this wonderful story
that they have made up now they claim
and it's a fact if you go to um so the
so in Tibet you have the Dal Lamas right
so I don't know which Dal Lama it was
the fourth or the sixth Dal Lama he was
born in tang in the city of
tawang okay this city of Tang which is
in arunachal Pradesh Tang is an
extremely holy place for Tibetan
Buddhism but it is in India in Arun in
arunachal Pradesh so the Chinese claim
that this should be part of Tibet and
they I don't know they made some excuse
and they said that it was part of Tibet
which means that arunachal Pradesh the
all the whole of arunachal Pradesh
should also be part of Chinese occupied
Tibet so that is the
incredible Fantastical fairy tale the
Chinese have created to stake a claim on
arunachal Pradesh now the Chinese claim
that the mcmah McMahan line which was
decided in 1914 between the British
Indian empire and the Tibetan Kingdom
the Chinese say that we don't recognize
that because whatever the Chinese don't
recognize the McMahan line that was
agreed upon in
1914 between British India and
Tibet so they claim that this line is
illegitimate and we will not recognize
it and arunachal should be ours but it
is funny that the same McMahan line the
Chinese refus to acknowledge or or uh
yeah acknowledge
for arunachal Pradesh the
Chinese they acknowledge the McMahan
line as legitimate when it comes to
their the border between China and
Burma because Burma at that time was
part of the British Indian empire it was
part of British India and the McMahan
line extended Beyond arunachal Pradesh
to the border between British Burma and
China so that part of the McMahan line
the Chinese agree to it agree to it but
the other part when it applies to India
they don't agree so this is double
standards it is a two-faced Behavior it
is hypocrisy the chines to make a long
story short have never ruled arunachal
they have no legitimate claim to Tibet
they are in illegal brutal
occupation of Tibet and they should be
evicted at the first possible
opportunity right now India is too weak
to do that thanks to the wonderful
economic and Military policies of our
governments and prime ministers in the
20th Cent Cy but hopefully now things
will change but we have to it's it's a
long road ahead of us so let's all
contribute in some way to strengthening
the
nation all
right sidhar Sharma says how do we
prepare for a future war with
China yeah we have to be prepared a war
between India and China could happen if
the Chinese become desperate or if the
Americans push India into a corner and
instigate a war or whatever happens you
know there's always the possibility that
India and China could go to war and that
such such a war would never be started
by India it will be started by China if
it ever happens now what should India do
about this China is way more powerful
than India China when it comes to the
cumulative hard power is about three and
a half to four times more powerful than
India but the good news is that China is
tied up if you look at China's various
borders they have territorial disputes
with every nation they are really
worried about the US military presence
in Taiwan they are really really really
in South Korea and in Japan so the
Americans have essentially encircled
China at Sea and that is a big big
problem for China the Chinese and and
the Chinese have territorial historical
territorial dis with Russia as well
right now they're kind of friends but
haha let's see how long that lasts the
Chinese need to deploy significant
forces in all these regions which means
they can deploy at best a quarter or a
third of their forces when it comes to
Bear against India along the India Tibet
border so and yet India may be somewhat
outmatched if India has to go to war
with China because China can on an
emergency basis push in more more forces
over here so what should India do so we
have to to heed the lessons of the
Russia Ukraine proxy war with with NATO
so what's happening in this proxy war we
are seeing horrible visuals every day on
social media
uh of this war the Russia Ukraine war we
are seeing fpv drones being
deployed firsters view
drones drones that can take out
individual soldiers one drone they can
take out tanks as well so a drone that
costs $400 or $500 a cheap drone can
take out a tank which is worth let's say
$10 million that's what we are seeing
and there are smaller drones that are
used as anti-personnel drones so one
drone kills one human being and these
are ghastly things that are happening
it's like flying mines nowaday and there
are Mine Fields everywhere which will
take centuries to clear disaster in
Ukraine the Russians and the ukrainians
are are are using tens of thousands of
drones every month using it's a one-time
use drones loitering Munitions suicide
drones whatever you want to call them
anti-personnel drones anti-tank drones
anti-vehicle drones loitering Munitions
suicide drones all these autonomous
vehicles remote control vehicles or even
autonomous vehicles you know they are be
used in the tens of thousands of year
every
month so the future Wars so it's like
the first world war in the 20th century
was was a completely new era it was the
beginning of new er era before the first
world war started the Warfare used to to
be Cavalry Charges horse riders and
sword fighting and and musk not muskets
you you had primitive rifles and all
that but the first world war was when
all of that was abandoned in favor of
mechanized Warfare tanks and artillery
and the first rudimentary aircraft and
all that it was a sea change in the type
of warfare so we are seeing the
beginning of that in the Ukraine
war 21st century Warfare is going to be
more of about autonomous vehicles about
REM control vehicles is going to be
about drones and so on there's going to
be less of an emphasis on
missiles Less on tanks and so on and you
eventually will have swarms of drones
like swarms of mosquitoes which will all
be controlled by Central Intelligence
could be an AI you may not even need
human inter intervention and you can
take out let's say 50% of a drone form
of a thousand and even even then the
remaining 500 could take out tremendous
numbers of targets you could have drone
swarms devastating aircraft carriers in
the future you know you can have anti
missile defense systems on aircraft
carriers but how will those defense
systems deal with
drones that to a swarm of drones let's
say 10,000 drones descend on an aircraft
carrier spinning in all kinds of ways
and avoiding each other through
Ai and even if 80% are taken out if 20%
that is 200 drones strike the aircraft
carrier it's going to devastate the
thing so that is the future of warfare
the Russians and the ukrainians both
sides are expending tens of thousands of
drones every
month so India is going to have to go
all in on these new technologies the
Chinese are already doing that they have
their robotic dogs and so on India will
have to go into
that uh and then missiles obviously are
important and you need stock piles of
tens of thousands of missiles not 200 of
this and 300 of that that's how the
Indian procurement system works so you
need to change that then you need to
India needs to bolster its Navy which is
very strangely
counterintuitive because China is up
north right the Himalayas I mean Chinese
occupied Tibet but the key to being
making China behave in the North in the
Himalayan region is to bolster India's
Naval abilities in the Indian Ocean
region because if India can blockade or
threaten to blockate the malaka stet and
everything else and cut off China's
access to this region then the Chinese
will have to
behave so India needs a much more
powerful navy we need to expand all of
this on a war footing a war could happen
any time you know uh and we need to
obviously have a long penetration
ability there's only a few roads that
that the Chinese have that go into Tibet
roads and railway lines you cut that cut
that off the Chinese soldiers in the
region are fighting on their own without
access to supplies
so that's what India has to do and of
course India needs to augment its
um its that Weapon It's stockpile of of
that weapon the WarHeads nuclear
warheads we need more we obviously have
the means to deliver the gift but we
need more gifts potential gifts so all
of that India will have to do and maybe
India will have to augment its defense
budget and so on so that's kind of what
India needs to do 21st century Warfare
is going to be very different from
everything we have experienced in the
past so India needs to
radically change the way it thinks about
war our air Air Force still talks about
dog fighting and all that that is 20th
century Warfare today you're going to
have autonomous vehicles autonomous
fighting drones and all that fighter
planes and all that that's going to
happen soon so we have to keep up with
the changes
next question pan 97 says Russia's
Vladimir Putin has invited Pakistan to
the
insc in um International north south
transport
Corridor uh trade Corridor isn't that a
bad move is the question as main the
agenda behind creating Pakistan of of
West was to make the main agenda of the
West in creating Pakistan was to make
sure that India doesn't access Central
Asia correct and Europe EUR Asia and the
uh reason for creating Pakistan was to
destabilize India lots of reasons for
creating Pakistan and Pakistan also
supports turkey and aeran in the
Armenian conflict how can a country like
Pakistan be trusted in
this okay good question so there has
been a news report that came out
recently that Pakistan will be
joining The Intern National North South
uh transport Corridor so where did this
news report come from this came from a
statement made by the Pakistani
ambassador to Russia his name is Khaled
ismile or Khaled jamali or something so
this gentleman the Pakistani ambassador
to Russia made the claim that according
to President Putin's Vision Pakistan
will be joining the
in uh International north south trade
Corridor Transportation Corridor that's
what the pakistanis are claiming have
the Russians made any statement about
this I'm not sure I've not seen any of
that that is point number one so the
Russians haven't officially said this
the pakistanis have made the claim that
is point number one now what is this
insdc International north south trade
Corridor it initially began as a Russia
India Iran project and the objective was
to
connect the western coast of the Indian
of of India's West Coast cities like
Mumbai ET Etc two cities in the Black
Sea region and Caspian Sea region with
ports in the region and to create a
trade connectivity Transportation
connectivity so that India can trade
with Eurasia it will help India it will
help the Central Asian Nations it will
help Russia it will certainly help
Iran and that's what it is that's the
insdc and let's go to Google and see
what the insc looks like
um
uh I'm sure we'll get some uh nice
uh cartographic representations in STC
right International north south
transport
Corridor okay let's see this okay if I
put this most people won't understand
the context so let us see a different
map so this is the kind of thing it is
it it connects Mumbai with chabahar
bandarabbas tan and various parts of the
Black Sea region sorry the Caspian
Sea uh asaran Volgograd Moscow St
Petersburg Helsinki Stockholm and so on
so forth through the Mediterranean Sea
through the Su Canal Red Sea baland and
back to mbai that's the kind of thing it
is okay so that is the international
north south trade Corridor
Transportation Corridor it began as a
India Russia Iran project now more
countries have joined what countries
have joined let's let's go back to the
map and let me show you what countries
have joined I may not be able to recall
all of
them but the countries in the region
will join so countries
like like aeran you can see aeran on the
map over here this is aeran then you
have uh Armenia let's go deeper into the
map
Armenia then Nations like
Kazakhstan and kyrgistan
Tajikistan and I believe turkey has also
joined Syria has also joined Ukraine
could be part part of it Belarus Oman
Syria so there are nations that are not
exactly along that that pathway but they
have also joined it means that these
nations can create their own
connectivity with the main
infrastructure of the ins STC and become
part of this uh of this project of this
Transportation Corridor so that's what
it is now what about Pakistan so we
don't have any confirmation Beyond a
Pakistani claim that this could happen
but what if the Russians want Pakistan
to join what does it mean so listen
Pakistan can join if they want they can
use this Corridor even even without
officially joining it that's okay the
international north south trade Corridor
alignment is through the Black Sea
through the Caspian Sea to the Indian
Ocean and from the Indian Ocean to the
Caspian Sea and VI that to Eurasia and
countries that want access to this can
join it by linking their infrastructure
their Road infrastructure their rail
infrastructure or whatever else to the
main infrastructure of the insdc like
the Central Asian Nations and other
nations have done so that's how it could
happen will it help
Pakistan I don't know how much it will
help Pakistan and if the Russians
actually have agreed to Pakistan joining
it what could it
mean see Russia has no special love for
Pakistan understand that Pakistan is not
some valuable country from Russia's
perspective the Russians have in the
past had some Dian da dialing with with
with the pakistanis in the past during
the
2015s from the period of 2015 to about
2021 22 about 21 or so when they had
some military exercises the DBA
exercises Etc but nowadays it's not the
case so if the Russians have actually
agreed let's say hypothetically through
Pakistan joining it it could only mean
that the Chinese have told them to do it
and Russia has to kind of exceed to some
of Chinese China's uh demands and why
would China want this to counter back
India in some way or the other so they
know that Pakistan from our perspective
is an irritant we don't want to have
anything to deal do with Pakistan we
don't want to deal with Pakistan right
India doesn't want that we want we want
to live our lives and not have to deal
with Pakistan we will not do anything to
Pakistan Pakistan can live its own life
in peace let them have their own
whatever they're doing but keep us out
of it that is that has been India's
perspect India's uh attitude towards
Pakistan since Mr Modi came to power and
especially since the URI thing in the
the surgical strikes and the balakot
thing right since then India has stopped
uh dealing with Pakistan we have the
bare minimum relations diplomatic
relations so if the Chinese are trying
to bring Pakistan into the picture it's
it's they're trying to annoy irritate
and offset India but it doesn't really
make much of a difference it doesn't
mean there's any normalization between
uh the relationship between India and
Pakistan or any such thing so Pakistan
obviously from your perspective and from
India's perspective we know Pakistan's
past history so we will obviously be
tremendously wary of Pakistan nothing
against the people of Pakistan but their
regime the Army regime is obviously a
terrorist regime and we simply can't
trust them so that's the deal so even if
Pakistan becomes part of it somehow it
doesn't really uh change too much for us
the main nations are going to be India
Russia and Iran in this Transportation
Corridor Ro sarar says why didn't the
USSR and USA divide Japan between
themselves after its unconditional
surrender in
1945 and why did the USSR allow Japan to
fall under Western
influence okay let's understand what
happened 1945 what
happened August 15 was it or whatever
the date was the Americans tested a
nuclear device on Hiroshima on the
people of Hiroshima that's why what they
did and then a few days later they
tested another nuclear device on the
people of
Nagasaki and then they threatened the
Japanese
uh government that we're going to test
more weapons on your people unless you
surrender and so the Govern government
of Japan decided to surrender to the US
so it was an unconditional surrender by
the government of Japan by the Japanese
Japanese empire Japanese emperor to the
government of the
US who did Japan surrender to they
surrendered to the us unconditionally on
board a warship aircraft carrier
Destroyer whatever it was the instrument
of surrender was signed on a
warship okay so the surrender the
unconditional surrender was to the US so
now when uh you get the unconditional
surrender of a Nation why would you
divide that and give that up to some
other Nation why what sense does it mean
what what sense does it
make why would you give some of that up
to a nation that's your rival the USS
are why why why that's not how the world
works if you get something you want you
want the whole pie you want the whole
pie you don't want to give some some of
the pie away to your Rivals why would
you do
that it makes no geopolitical sense why
did the USSR allow Japan to fall under
Western influence the West had much
better power projection abilities and
the West was able to do what they they
were able to achieve their objectives
who was fighting the Pacific Pacific War
you have to understand the history of
the Second World War to to understand
what happened who was fighting the war
in the Pacific the Americans were they
had this tremendous power projection
ability even then much uh obviously now
it's much much better but they were
fighting the Japanese in in the Pacific
region they had the Battle of Midway and
so on and it was the Americans that were
able to defeat Japan the USSR was
fighting the war in Europe it is the
USSR that did most of the bleeding and
most of the fighting and most of the
winning in Europe and today the
Americans take credit for what happened
in Europe it is the Russians it is the
Soviets who defeated Germany in Europe
it's not the Americans who did that most
of the fighting most of the winning was
done by the USSR so their entire Focus
was in Europe when it comes to the USSR
because it was an existential threat for
the
USSR when it comes to the US they had no
existential threats the US was a
continent away over here and they had no
threats so they could just go their
merry way and fight it out with whoever
they wanted so they were essentially
fighting a war in which they there was
no real serious threat to them the
Americans and the Russians were fighting
a war for their own Survival for their
existence so that's the
difference so that's why the USSR could
not defeat Japan they were too busy
fighting and defeating the the the Nazis
Hitler and that's how the Americans took
Japan the whole of Japan and obviously
uh there is a territorial dispute
between Japan and Russia when it comes
to the kural islands and technically
second the second world war has not
ended over here because uh uh ceasefire
has never been signed between Japan and
the USSR and now the successor state of
the USSR is Russia so technically you
could say the second world war is still
on
between Japan and Russia and the
Japanese uh well the sakhalin islands
were historically Japanese sorry the the
kural islands were historically Japanese
but now they are part of Russia if you
look here just next just just Northeast
of Hokkaido you have kunashir which is a
Russian held Island you have all these
little Islands which are also Russian
Hill Islands but historically they were
Japanese and there's a whole
geopolitical angle to those islands very
very important Islands critical Islands
from the Japanese from the US
perspective and also for the for the
Russians and I have videos about that so
you can look it up if you are interested
so that is essentially what
happened okay a long question by sa
Mahmud uh yeah as you said power Trump's
wealth which is definitely true but
there's some confusion regarding this
you gave the example of Jack ma in China
which is basically a communist
country but is it relevant in the
context of the US UK and other
capitalist countries or even India I
have also learned from you that actually
the real power in the US lies completely
outside the democratically elected
government among these power holders
there are some billionaire oligarchs who
because of their immense wealth wield
significant power and use it primarily
to further increase their wealth doesn't
it show that wealth is often equated
with power or something else how do we
reconcile these perspectives excellent
question yes I gave the example of Jack
M China's richest person and then what
happened he disapp appeared for quite
some time I I'm not sure if he has
reappeared but yeah in China you may be
the richest person in the country
officially but a a simple City municipal
level official of the Chinese Communist
Party
can actually has more actual power
compared to you what does it mean he can
put you in jail he can shut down your
company he can come and have your
buildings broken down smashed down
that's what the Chinese Communist Party
can do on demand what is power in the
rawest and truest sense it is the the
ability to effect very rapid change
constructive or
destructive and the scary change is
destructive
simple power is treat power you have a
100 heavily armed men who will obey you
instantaneously without question that is
power okay that is power okay can money
buy you that sometimes money can buy you
that but uh often money can't buy you
that so jackma can't buy such power in
China because the Chinese Communist
party has a monopoly on that on that
brute power Street power muscle power
gun power jackma simply can't do that
now what about the US let's take the
example of Elon Musk H can El Elon Musk
buy a private Army thousand heavily
armed men who will instantaneously obey
him without question can Elon Musk do
that he
cannot can Bill Gates do that no no no
no so does that wealth that you have buy
you that power that hard power no but
let's say you are deep inside the
government you don't have that much
wealth but you have access to the
military to to the police and they will
do what you say because you're part of
the government and you can issue the
orders that is power and remember Elon
Musk
was he was based out of California and
he had to move out of California to I
think Texas or somewhere or Delaware to
Texas whichever state to Texas they they
made him move out by you know through
their policies the policies were so bad
that he had to move out he could not
even operate in that state where's the
power
so it doesn't matter how much wealth you
really have it is the people who wield
the instruments of policy and power and
and the hard power which is the military
army navy Air Force and police on the
streets they are the ones who are really
in power so a
simple let's say I don't know what
police chief in the US can actually have
more power than Elon
Musk uh you know a city level police a
mayor let's say mayor
a city mayor if can actually shut down
Elon musk's Giga factories or whatever
he wants because by by you know making
some excuse that they have violated
violated so and so legislation or so and
so whatever they can do that that is
power the power to affect very rapid
change like that and typically that that
change is destructive
change and once you are deep inside the
inside the government then obviously you
can acquire more power and influence
through wealth so wealth if you are
already powerful then wealth can buy you
more power but if you are powerless then
no matter how much wealth you have you
will not be able to buy Power unless you
understand what power is and learn how
to wield it acquire it and wield it and
power is a very mysterious
thing and explaining that is a well it
could take time or maybe it's not for
everyone what power really
is so so yeah Building Wealth doesn't
guarantee any power so the point is
wealth cannot be equated with power if
you are powerless and you have a
tremendous amount of wealth you will not
be able to buy Power with that wealth
but if you already have some power and
you have more and you have wealth then
you can use that wealth to acquire more
power so you need to First understand
what power is you need to acquire some
power you need to know how to use it
wield it and then you can use wealth to
multiply that power augment that power
so that's how is power is very
straightforward it is the same whether
it it's in China or the us or in
Botswana or in India or wherever power
is
power knowledge is not power power is
power all
right you know where that comes from
right okay next question balam Putin
says one of the core goals of La
Revolution Fran the French Revolution
was to eliminate monarchy my question is
after is that after the French
Revolution Napoleon took control of
France France as a ruler so can we
consider the revolution as a failure
then it's an interesting point that you
make so you have the French
Revolution and they bring down the the
aristocracy the monarchy the the
decapitate the guillotine the King Louis
the 16th the gutin Mari onet they
claimed that she said that let the
people eat cake or something they make
up all these fake quotes and fake news
about her and they they behead the king
they behead his his his wife the queen
Mar anet and there's a reign of terror
in France in Paris and everybody who has
some blue blood some nobility some some
Noble or aristocratic blood Etc is
beheaded decapitated and so on and then
robier one of the major instigators of
this he himself gets be beheaded he he
becomes a victim of his own success so
to say and and so on so that's kind of
what happens in the revolution the
French Revolution and then you have the
great ideals of
Lial frat Liberty equality fraternity
and then the idea of Lac comes in
secularism
also and and so what happens is that the
you know in any
nation in any nation in any culture it
is the the 1% of the 1% who set the
standards for the N for the entire
it is the 1% of the one person that
small group the people with the highest
standards that set the standards for the
entire nation that everybody else
follows it's not the average person who
sets the standards it is the people with
the higher standards who set a benchmark
and then everybody follows that or or
tries to follow that and that's how you
proud of your of your country and its
achievements and all
that so so what the French Revolution
did is that it killed
off the cream of its cream the all the
best people the best people typically
are the highest Achievers and that's why
they rise to the top it doesn't mean
they have been exploiting everybody else
it means they are just
better and of course it's going to be a
self-perpetuating system a class system
in India they call it a cast system
whatever you want to call it there's
going to be distinctions in society
levels and stress certification and
division of labor and whatnot it is
natural in any any functioning Society
overtime Society organizing organizes
itself in this manner so what the French
Revolution did is that it killed off its
nobility aristocracy all the people with
the standards and then there was
mobocracy the rule of the law the rule
of the Mob of the
Rabel and in France descended into chaos
and Anarchy and standards fell
abis it was it was the rule of the mob
and then and when all this chaos was
happening there was this guy called
Napoleon buap who was born in Cora
okay it was then a Venetian Island
Italian island and uh long story short
I'll not go into his story because it's
a very interesting story I've spoken
about it in the past I'm sure but then
when the French Revolution is happening
he goes back to Cora stays out of it and
he comes back to France and within a
very short period of time less than 20
years almost 20 years he goes from an
absolutely nobody obscure person to the
emperor of France and Italy and he
convinces
he convinces the people who who carried
out the French Revolution that the only
way to
continue and and and and to achieve the
objectives of the French Revolution is
to crown him as the emperor so the
revolution which started by killing off
the nobility aristocracy and the King
ended by crowning this guy as the
emperor he actually convinced them to do
that and then he went to war with
everybody under the son and eventually
he overextended himself and his end was
pretty
Swift uh so that's the deal with
Napoleon so is the revolution a failure
not quite yeah it ended farcically with
Napoleon becoming the Emperor of not
just France but also Italy and fighting
the whole world essentially but many of
the changes that the revolution brought
about have been longlasting
So eventually there was a return to to
to uh to aristocracy to
to monarchy Etc there was written for
some time and all that but many of the
changes that that the revolution brought
in like
Lial Etc the rule of the mob so to say
Etc they still continue you still see
that in French society and government
and the French government still today
talks about the ideals of the French
Revolution okay so there were permanent
changes that happened in French society
as a result of this and you some some
could claim some would claim that the
standards of France dropped abysmally
dropped significantly after that many
French people would be genuinely
offended and horrified and they would be
uh you know deeply offended by anyone
making such a suggestion but we are
Outsiders we are dispassionate external
observers we are not emotionally
invested in all these matters we get
emotional when people talk about
India but we can talk about other
countries
I think more or less dispassionately and
they can get emotional about that about
us talking about them so let it let's
let's reverse the Gaze for a change so I
think that the revolution did not
entirely U fail it did bring about
lasting changes overall it I think it it
caused a lowering of standards in France
if France had remained a monarchy then
it would have had higher standards uh
the revolution the French Revolution was
like kind of the first voke Revolution
because it it killed of the the people
the performers the people of the high
standards and brought about the rule of
the mob mob Justice the rule of the
Rebel and so on so not entirely a
failure okay rodra sarar says can you
tell us something about the Hungarian
revolution of
1956 was this revolution
successful so the Hungarian revolution
of 1956 you know 1956 was an interesting
time lots of interesting geopolitical
events happened in 1956 for example the
sus crisis which I have spoken about in
the past the Su crisis happened in the
Suz Canal region when the British the
French and the Israelis tried to conquer
uh Egypt take over the Suz canal and the
Americans prevented that and that
essentially was the end of the UK as a
first class Global power it became a
third class Global power after that now
coming back to the Hungarian Revolution
same year 1956 a few months after the
sus crisis so the Hungarian revolution
of 1956 was a nationwide re Revolt in
Hungary against the communist
government of Hungary the Hungarian
People's Republic I believe which was a
Soviet puppet and the policies of this
government were Soviet imposed policies
so Hungary was a was a member of the
warso block at the time okay and this
Revolt Revolution whatever you want call
it it took place in the last quarter of
uh 1956 October November somewhere
around that time and it was kind of a
very important event during the Cold War
it
demonstrated how much discontent was
existed against the Soviet control in
Eastern Europe so what happened is that
Hungary like all the Eastern block
countries was under strict Soviet
control there were Soviet puppets there
were Soviet wasal and the ruling party
was a Communist Party the the working
people's party and they imposed Soviet
dictated policies harsh policies
censorship suppression of political
descent you cannot go against the party
you cannot go say anything against the
Soviet Union or anything and they would
perceive they would persecute perceived
enemies of the state and all that so
there was all this stuff then there was
economic hardship because you had
economic policies that led to widespread
poverty there were shortages of basic
Goods there were poor living standards
that's what happens under communism
socialism Etc there was collectivization
of Agriculture there was forced
industrialization and overall very poor
living standards as a result of this and
there were other uprisings for example
there was something that that happened
in in Poland that year that also could
have uh contributed this they that could
have inspired the Hungarian Revolution
or revolt and then you have students and
intellectuals who who were demanding
political reforms they were demanding
freedom of speech they were demanding
the withdrawal of Soviet troops from the
country
yeah uh and so on so all that was the
backdrop
again be against which the events of the
last quarter of 56 took place so there
was in October there was a peaceful
student demonstration in Buddha PES
which mushroomed which snowballed into a
large protest and there were demanding
reforms and withdrawal of USSR troops
and all that and then the the the police
fired upon the crowd and then the
protest became violent it became an
armed Insurrection and these uh
protesters initially very quickly took
control of the of key locations in
Buddha PES and then this protest this
Uprising spread to other cities in
Hungary and the government
collapsed and uh there was a guy who was
a reform minded communist leader Nagi he
was appointed as the new prime minister
of Hungary and this guy promised reforms
he said there will be free elections he
said that Hungary will become a neutral
country and he wanted to withdraw from
the from the voo pact so initially the
USSR appeared to be willing to negotiate
and some Soviet troops actually began to
withdraw from Hungary but then there was
the prospect that this would lead to a
domino effect and it would encourage
other War so packed countries Eastern
block countries to rebel and go out of
the Soviet zone of influence so then
because of that the Soviets decided to
crush the revolution so in early
November
56 a large Soviet military force invaded
Hungary they very quickly overwhelmed
the Hungarian
forces and in a few days the Revolution
was completely crushed thousands of
people hungarians were killed many more
were arrested many hungarians fled the
country and and that's essentially what
happened and Soviet control was
reasserted over Hungary and a new Pro
USSR government was installed under
yanosh
Kadar and then there were harsh harsh
reprisals against people thousands of
people were imprisoned or executed or
exiled and so on and so on so forth so
this is what the Hungarian revolution of
1956 was it was not successful it failed
because the USSR was way too powerful
but it demonstrated what were the
weaknesses of the USSR which would which
would eventually contribute to the
breakup of the USSR so the uprising was
crushed but it inspired future
generations of of reformers and it
eventually uh you know it it brought out
the fault lines and the weaknesses and
deficiencies in the Soviet model of
governance in in communism and socialism
and all that and that those are the
factors that eventually led to the
breakup of the USSR and the fall of of
the gorbachov government
eventually Sor borya says the chandogya
Brahman talks about a king who is
establishing a settlement on the banks
of the sarasti where it is facing the
ocean today's deserted area of Gujarat
and Rajasthan okay Rajasthan doesn't
really face the ocean but okay uh and
people there were cultivating Pearl
millets now paleontologists have found
elephant bones in that region with which
is clear indications of a Forest because
elephants live in forests not deserts
which now became a deserted land which
is at least 4,000 years old okay and
also milet farming was also discovered
in this region how could Arians know all
these things if they came outside look
the Arian Invasion migration tourism
picnic thing is a myth we know that uh
so I'm not sure what's written in this
text but uh what we what's to be
understood is let's go to the map once
again so we have a tar desert
today and the tar desert okay let's go
to the satellite
image so the region of the Thar Desert
this desertified region in Western India
and some parts of Pakistan okay why is
it a desert today it used to be once
the it used to be a kind of a lake so if
you go to the uh for example the Aral SE
region today there I can't even find the
Aral SE anymore right okay this region
the araly region I think this is Aral is
it let me once again go to
that
um I think this is the Ari region it's
it's a desert today it used to be the
bottom of a sea in the past similarly
there used to be a big lake kind of
thing over here where the sarasti river
dried out in the past and that is
eventually what became the tar
desert uh now so the point is that that
was once a lush green region what is now
a desert and the sarasti dried out out
because of a steady monotonic decline in
the Indian rain season beginning about
6,000 BC which is about 8,000 years
before today so 8,000 years before today
the the Indian Monsoon Indian rainy
season was at its peak intensity and
from that time onwards it started
declining slowly slowly very gradually
very imperceptibly but by 1500 BC it
caused much of the sarasa to dry
out okay so the Indian season was way
heavier than it is today a few thousand
years ago so when we look at you know
artistic representations of haraa M
kalibangan raki gari Etc we let's let's
let's Google it right very quickly let's
Google what artistic representations of
harapa madoro
are so let's go to
Google
uh
Hara uh see when you see artistic
depictions you will see it all
yellow the artists when they depict Hara
this is an AI generated Dage let's
forget about that but generally when
artists make drawings of harapa moo they
draw it like this completely Brown
yellowish Baron the fact is that it was
completely lush green the monsoon was
way way heavier than what it is today as
you can see everybody does the same
mistake they all there's not a tree
inide right when these wonderful
intelligent artists do these drawings
okay over here there is somebody who
made a small Forest but overall they'll
show it is completely Barron and this
desert around it that was not the case
it was lush green lush
green and yeah you had forests all over
the place so there's no surprise that
you you would have found elephant uh I'm
sorry not this you would have found
elephant remains in this region and you
would have cultivation of all kinds of
crops including joar Baja pear millets
other kinds of milary barley whatever
you want to call it all of that and the
Arian Invasion thing come on now let's
not go into that it's
a it's what Arian in Invasion then
migration then tourism then picnic then
what alien invasion whatever come on man
it's it's a it's a myth it's a complete
myth and I'll not go into the reasons
why it's a myth I've spoken about that
often
enough mavin 69 says was Gaddafi good
leader is that why he was killed muamar
Gaddafi was a colonel colonel Gaddafi
and when I was a kid he was like in his
prime essentially and he was standing up
against the Americans and the Americans
bombed trioli I believe and they killed
one of his daughters one of his little
kids and all that so uh that's in the
80s but uh Gaddafi was eventually killed
in what 20 10 2011 somewhere around that
time when Obama was in power and uh you
know what the lady said the former
Secretary of State Hillary Clinton we
came we saw and he died ha that's what
he said
so he was killed by us supported uh
let's say Freedom Fighters when the
Americans support somebody those people
are obviously always invariably Freedom
Fighters and later on they can trans
grify into terrorists at will whatever
so what Gaddafi wanted he wanted a
United he wanted to create a United
States of Africa with a common currency
and he had the gold reserves to back
that currency with
gold I mean I'm not sure how much gold
he had but he had significant amounts of
gold all of that gold is now in US hands
obviously naturally that's where gold
belongs with us so he wanted to create a
United States of Africa he wanted a gold
backed currency an African dinar or
something and that's obviously how dare
he how dare you do that it's a challenge
to the hemony of the US Empire right I
mean imagine during the Roman times if
if uh Judea were to rebel and say that
we going to create our own currency and
we're going to have our own Union of
States I mean would the Roman
Empire countenance that obviously they
would not imagine Germania all the
Germanic tribes uniting and creating a
confederation United States of Germania
and having their own German Mark of the
time gold back Mark do you imagine the
Roman emperors would would tolerate that
obviously not so that's what happened so
that's what they say is why why he was
killed off because he was an
inconvenient ruler was he a good
leader
look living standards were great in
Libya when he was the rer obviously he
was a dictator obviously he was an
autocrat obviously some people they say
would have been marginalized during his
rule similar to how things were in Iraq
during Saddam Hussein's time Saddam
Hussein Alti obviously he was a dictator
obviously he was brutal towards some
people but overall you had excellent Law
and Order you had zero religious clashes
you had zero sectarian clashes Iraq was
a secular Nation genuinely secular
Nation men and women had equal
rights what is Iraq like today how was
Libya during muhamad Gaddafi's time I
think they had free education free
healthare that's something I've been
saying that we need in
India in any civilized country education
and healthare should be subsidized by
the state should be completely free tax
the people but give free education and
free healthare I think Gaddafi was doing
that as far as I know and those Law and
Order everything obviously there would
be some repression of people of some
certain kinds of people who would be
against him which is natural I mean do
you think the US doesn't oppress and
repress its own people what about the
Native Americans aren't they second
class or third class citizens in the US
until recently wen't the the African
Americans the Latinos Hispanics Etc
second class citizens so who are they to
I mean look in the mirror first
right so look I think he was a
reasonably good leader obviously he was
a dictator obviously if if he did not
like you life was not good for
you remember Emperor Ashok one of the
greatest Emperors we've had it was
dangerous to be near him he was a
dangerous person he killed off lots of
people he was cruel he was brutal but he
was great for
batsh if you lived in in the Indian
subcontinent during the rule of Ashok as
long as you were far from him you had
excellent living standards and India was
a great culture Society civilization at
the time and ashoke was was instrumental
in India's
but he was a dangerous person to be near
and you better not be on his bad side
that's how it was so maybe Saddam
Hussein Gaddafi Etc with that s of
people on a smaller scale Akbar I mean
as I'm sorry what am I saying Ashok was
obviously the ruler of an entire
subcontinent gigantic Empire Saddam
Hussein was the ruler of Iraq and
Gaddafi was the ruler of Libya and they
were both killed off by the us because
well their time was up as far as the
Americans were concerned
udit Mahesh says would you consider
Banning homework in schools as a first
step in reforming the education system I
myself did not do homework at home and I
still got very good marks in the final
exam when I was in school look there's
so much that needs to be done when it
comes to reforming the education system
but I believe that homework is an
atrocity homework is an atrocity I hated
homework as a kid okay it doesn't help
you in anything anyway whatsoever you
already spending five six hours a day in
school
and your teachers aren't able to teach
you well enough that you have to go and
spend another four hours 5 hours a day
at home doing homework why why do you
need that children need to have some
time to play they need to have lots of
time outside
Outdoors doing doing things that are fun
and and you know that that is
besides uh school
work so I believe that if if a kid if a
child if a 10-year-old if an 8-year-old
if a 15year old is spending six hours a
day in school or whatever that should be
enough homework is simply laziness it
means teachers aren't able to do what
they're supposed to do and they are
putting the onus on the child himself or
herself or maybe the parents or whoever
so I think homework is useless you can
utilize five or five or six hours a day
in school if it is utilized properly
that's more than enough to impart
sufficient education to a child but you
need to have good teachers and we have
abysmal teachers in India okay so let me
not get started about this I believe
that homework is an atrocity homework
should be abolished teachers should take
full responsibility for what they are
doing five or six hours a day is enough
in school that's what I believe and when
it comes to reforming the education
system I have spoken enough I have three
three or four episodes of ask abijit
dedicated only to that check it out
around episode 30 give or take two three
check it
out grateful pixel says nowadays we see
many people accusing the Indian diet of
having too much carbohydrates and very
little protein which is the reason we
also leading in is this the re reason we
are leading in diabetes historically was
the Indian diet always like this okay
this is a controversial topic let me
tell you my perspective and I am see
simply seeing it from the perspective of
facts facts not
facts facts the Indian
diet what we call the traditional Indian
diet today is extremely carbohydrate
heavy and extremely deficient in protein
this is a fact especially when it comes
to the vegetarian diet
it is extremely carbohydrate heavy and
extremely deficient in protein what do
you eat let's say standard meal in a
metropolitan City morning you eat a Dosa
or idly or or medu or sambar then
afternoon you will eat rice with
something or Roti with some subzi and
evening you will have some M what
whatever other subzi and Roti and rice
with some sweet what gulab jamun or
whatever and that's your
diet it's all carbohydrates and sugar
where's the protein okay so Dal will
have a little bit of protein but it
comes wrapped in carbohydrates where is
the protein if you are a male you need
what you need two grams of protein per
pound which is one what is it one gram
of protein per pound right which is two
grams of protein per kilo roughly so if
you weigh 70 kilos you
need what 140 grams of protein a day
okay maybe that's too much maybe that's
the Western standards okay let's make it
half at least 70 gam of protein will you
eat but you're not getting
that so I'm not saying you need to
become meat eaters I'm not saying that
at all I'm saying you need to change
your diet and and and ensure there's
more protein that's coming to into your
that and you can get lots of protein
from vegetarian sources from meat from
cheese or paneer or or from from various
kinds of Pulses from lentils and so on
but ensure you get sufficient protein
and some people would say that I
attacking the Indian traditional diet
are you kidding me we're talking about
the starvation diet the in what we
consider to be the Indian traditional
diet today is actually the starvation
diet which we were forced into adopting
over two and a half centuries of British
rule because the British they created
hundreds of artificial famines in India
and Indians had to adapt their diet to
somehow survive all this so that
eventually became tradition just like
the PARTA and all that is a tradition
today which was never
Indian so we have to understand what
happened what we were forced to do I
don't think the Indian traditional diets
before the foreign occupation of India
were so carb heavy I'm sure there was a
lot more protein but we don't have those
cookbooks Etc because we've lost that
every we've lost everything in the
destruction of the Indian education
system and libraries and so on so forth
I'll not go go into that historically
our diet would have been much more
balanced I'm not saying we want to have
a protein heavy diet and carb light diet
I'm saying we need to have a balance of
macronutrients protein carbs fats
roughly one third one/ third one/ thir
that's how it should be roughly and
obviously it depends on your gender also
if you're a female you don't need that
much protein if you're male and
depending on how leisurely your act your
life is or how strenuous your daily life
is you may need to adjust that if you
are let's say an athlete if you are
let's say a construction worker you will
need 140 or 150 grams of protein a day
if you are a sedentary person sitting at
a desk you may need at least 70 grams of
protein a day but you need protein my
point is you need to look at it from a
from a in a dispassionate manner uh from
a non-emotional perspective and
understand that every human being needs
a balanced diet
and if you look at the macronutrients of
what you're eating you will find that it
is extremely carbohydrate heavy and
carbohydrates not fats are what cause
obesity and
diabetes get it
right copile 262 says is Interstellar
the best movie of the 21st century is it
true that Steven Spielberg stole the
idea of ET the Extraterrestrial from
Roy the alien and according to you
who is the greatest director ever look
uh Interstellar is one of the good
movies one of the great movies of the
21st century I would not say it's the
greatest I'm not sure which is the
greatest but one of the great movies for
sure and obviously one of my favorite
genres which is science fiction so I
really like the movie I don't mind
seeing it again on the big screen I
believe it's going to come out sometime
this year again on the big screen if it
does come out on the big screen I will
ensure that I I go and watch it one more
time so I like it very much I'm not sure
if if it's the best movie of the 21st
century but one of the great movies okay
is it true that Steven Spielberg stole
the idea of ET the Extraterrestrial from
satjit R is the alien yes it is believed
that plagiarized the alien which is a
story of screenplay by sh and the long
story sh had collaborated in some way
with some American guy who who
surreptitiously registered himself as
the copyright holder or the co-
copyright holder of the story with and
then he made many copies of the script
the screenplay and he publish and he
essentially distributed them all across
Hollywood so there were like dozens of
copies of this script floating around
Hollywood Steven Spielberg gets that and
then his movie ET comes up in 1982 or
whatever year it was and it is very
similar to the concept that Ste that
satjit Ray had in his screenplay of the
alien which is an benign not dangerous
not not hostile alien life form
extraterrestrial life form comes to the
planet Earth and befriends a
kid okay nobody had thought of that
story line earlier Roy came up with that
in the alien and Steven Spielberg most
likely plagiarized that so that is just
what it is I am no big fan of shat Dr
okay uh he is considered to be probably
India's greatest
director his movies they they they
glamorize
poverty so I I don't like his movies
okay don't hate me for it my perspective
you don't have to agree with me but
I you know poverty glorification and all
that I just can't stand that
glorification of misery and poverty
romantici ation of of poverty and misery
it's not my thing okay there is no
Beauty in poverty there is no Beauty in
misery but that's what his movies are
all about I'm sure there is a lot more
to that but the fact that there is so
much poverty and it's it's depicted at
something glorious I can't stand that
obviously I could be wrong I could be
completely you know
completely on the wrong track about this
but that's just how I see it not my
favorite director but over here you are
right that Steven Spielberg plagiarized
sh jra's script screenplay of the
alien uh who is the greatest director
ever I don't know man there are so many
great directors so many I mean Akira
Kurosawa he inspired so many Hollywood
movies um the what the Seven Samurai
what's the movie they made out of that
uh the American movie there's so many
movies they made that Stanley cubrick is
a great director and uh so many more I
mean I could give you hundreds of
examples but yeah uh there's no just
like I don't have one favorite music
band one favorite music genre one
favorite actor actress whatever
similarly I don't have one favorite
director there's so many Quentin tantino
I'm a big fan of Quentin tantino uh most
of his movies are really unique and and
great so I could give lots of examples
okay uh that brings me to the end of
this now let's take some questions from
the from the live chat The Magnificent
Seven that's right dearon you are
absolutely
right
Haim isama okay I'm not sure who that is
but I look it up thank you for
recommending that name I will check it
out Rashon yes Rashon good movie great
movie I love
it um shagun says rajat chopra's
question what is Raj chopra's question
I don't know there's so many questions
on the screen that I'm not able to see
it if I see it I'll I'll check it out R
Cha's question I'm trying to see it I'm
trying to see
it uh prti says what's my I I took the
question I think it's the first or
second question I took the US move on
Tibet they don't care about Tibet it's
just about creating a bigger Rift
between India and China and making the
two Nations fight and essentially
painting in India into Corner that's
what the American objective is they
simply do not care about Tibet otherwise
they would have done something about it
long
ago Ras Raj haad says I do consume 250
gam of CD above 50 gram of paneer 250 ml
of milk 500 gram of anyal and five roues
which is in the combination of wheat
flour and ground flour the ratio 2 is to
one okay I'm not sure what the macros
are but it looks like a good amount of
protein and and obviously you need to
determine how many calories you want you
want to ingest every day depending on
what your workload is what your activity
level is if you're lifting heavy every
day or if you're running sprinting every
day you would need 3,000 plus calories
but if you're sitting on a desk all day
2,000 is sufficient so it depends but
yeah what I'm seeing here is is a very
decent amount of protein for sure and
and carbs as well so ensure you get
fiber Etc from raw vegetables and all
that because you need fiber for good
digestion and and so on and yeah you'll
get a decent amount of fat from CD and
paneer as well so overall good diet but
ensure you get sufficient fiber from raw
vegetables
or cooked vegetables
fiber um mckl says what's your views on
hydrogen car so when you're talking
about hydrogen C I'm talking about I
believe you're talking about fuel cells
right which are based on hydrogen so
hydrogen fuel cells could actually be
more efficient eventually than your
lithium ion batteries lithium ion
batteries are these gigantic things that
are at the bottom of your electric
vehicles when it comes to fuel cells
which run on hydrogen they could be much
smaller than um than lithium than
lithium batteries and they would pollute
the planet much less so it is I think a
technology that is worthwhile it needs
to be invested in invested in more
research more R&D needs to be done I
think it could eventually turn up to be
a superior technology to the lithium ion
uh technology that we currently use so
yeah it's something that needs more R&D
and I'm sure that's happening I'm sure
that's happening
um himalay Chan says why is no one talk
about talking about climate change we
talk about climate change I've spoken
about it some of the significant times
if if you have a question I can take it
up but
yeah okay rajat says what okay this is
the question is
it that shagun was talking about okay
what would happen if we adopt a single
world currency what challenges will it
pose and what will and will that be
really of any advantage if you have a
single world currency you're going to
have a single entity or organization or
country that controls that currency that
owns the currency you know you can say
that it this currency belongs to the
entire world but eventually the most
powerful countries will end up owning it
and then eventually one country will end
up owning it so if you have a single
world
currency it could be a very dangerous
scenario in which a single nation or a
single entity organization could take
over the entire world like a one world
government and then they could impose
their will on the world they could turn
the the world into a monoculture and
into a single Empire is that good for
you I think the world is beautiful
because of diversity a genuine diversity
not fake and forced diversity I want
diversity in the sense that if I go to a
different country if I fly from here to
there or wherever everywhere I go I see
a different language different kind of
clothing that people wear different
culture different uh Customs all that
different different skin tones all that
is beautiful I go to Southeast Asia I
want to see different culture different
Lang angues different skin tones
different people I go to Africa I want
to see something different I go to
Europe I want to see something different
I go to the Middle East I want to see
something different you go to different
parts of the world you see different
cultures different Lifestyles different
way ways of life different languages
different Cuisines different cultures
different skin tones that is diversity
that is beautiful the world is is
beautiful because of that
diversity but if you impose a
monoculture all over the world everybody
wears the same clothes everybody has the
same education system everybody has the
same language the same religion it
destroys the beauty of the world and
this entire thing is a dangerous Ploy in
you know if you have a single B currency
so I am against a single B currency let
there be lots of currencies that was
also diversity but let's have all
currencies valued on the same thing
let's say the price of gold that would
be good so yeah that's and and then each
currency could represent the strength
and weaknesses of the local economy I
think that is a better way than having a
single world currency which is very
dangerous uh
um
okay um okay swastic says you just
discussed that various uh websites on
the internet are not reliable for
history are not so reliable and uh most
of them could have some biases obviously
so which publisher should I read here's
the deal
sir every publisher has some
bias especially when it comes to history
and culture and so on so for when it
comes to science Etc it's fine okay
science is just science it's all facts
generally generally when it comes to
history and all that you will have
biases so all the history books that I
own I have lots I've got way more than
you can see they all have some
distortions and some biases I have when
I'm I'm talking about books that talk
about India the best books that I would
recommend they also have biases and
distortions so what do you do about this
you have to first understand what are
the preval
biases what are the prev prevalent
distortions what are the the the
distortions and and and falsehoods that
are taken as self-evident by all
mainstream authors so you first have to
become aware of that and then you can
read books and be aware that you will
find these distortions and you don't
believe that but you read everything
else that's of value and acquire take
whatever is of value in those books so
what publisher should you read read as
much as possible I will not recommend
any one single single publisher the
world is not that simple that you read
this one book and everything is
done okay you got to read a lot so
explore your curiosity let your
curiosity drive you forward in different
directions read as much as possible in
whatever time you have but be aware that
much of it could be distorted and biased
that's how you go about it there's no
one book I can recommend or one
publisher I can
recommend so yeah that's kind of the
answer
um K says is egg wedge or non wedge
well is milk wedge or non wedge answer
me that riddle me this is milk wedge or
non wedge milk doesn't come from plants
it comes from an animal right usually
cows
buffal that's other animals you know the
Mongols drink milk from what horse
mares the Arabs drink milk from Camels
and so on okay my point is I'll not list
out all the animals that give milk is
milk wedge or non wedge in India milk
paneer Etc CD is regarded as a
vegetarian product right because you
don't kill any animal animal for that
but it's an animal product actually so
the vegans will not eat drink milk or
eat cheese or water because it's it's
not vegan but we vegetarians I mean
Indian vegetarians or or vegetarians
overall will eat that similarly egg well
if it's a non-fertilized egg it's not
not going to give life then you could
perhaps see it as as wedge but I think
most vegetarians will not prefer to
would not like to eat eggs so it's I
would say entirely subjective it's like
asking you whether a tomato is a fruit
or a plant or or or or a vegetable it's
a reproductive structure of a plant okay
so it's it's subjective answer so I
would say most vegetarians would say
that eggs are not whether they
fertilized or not but it's up to you
whether you want to eat it or
not soap says please answer my question
okay I don't see your question
sir I don't know what's your question I
don't know I can't find a question you
should have taken the opportunity to ask
the question there
anyhow the says suggest a high protein
vegetarian diet uh look you need to have
variety you can have different kinds of
pulses like uh kidney beans Raja and and
and and chickpeas which is ch
and various kinds of DS Like Ur Dal and
T and CH D and all those DS and you can
have
uh yogurt curd which is thei you can
have uh paneer which is cottage cheese
you can have milk so there's a lot of
protein in all these different sources
you actually if you're a vegetarian and
you're not and you're okay with having
carbs with your protein then you have a
tremendous amount of variety that
non-vegetarians don't have nonv people
have to eat just uh two or three
different kinds of meat that's it it's
very boring so uh that's a high protein
veg diet and obviously you have to eat
lots of vegetables with that because you
need fiber otherwise you will have
digestive problems so you do that and
obviously you can have some rice or
whatever with that chapatis Roes patas
for some extra carbs if you want that so
that will take care of your protein
requirements if you have that in the
sufficient qu in sufficient quantities
okay lots of questions let me take one
or two more and then we're done because
we have gone past two
hours
um Samar says how can we reduce trade
deficit with China by becoming a
manufacturing power Manu a big
manufacturing power and exporting more
finished products to China not just raw
materials right now what's happening is
is that India is not that big on
manufacturing we are exporting raw
materials to China and importing
finished goods and products from China
we need to start doing the opposite okay
we don't need let's say raw material
from China but we need to start
exporting more finished goods from China
and if required we can impose tariffs on
Chinese Goods if they are dumping too
much garbage in India so that's kind of
what you do obviously that's there's a
lot more to that but that is overall the
the manner in which you
proceed
um all right let's
uh let's see one more okay geopolitical
dub says your take on Elon musk's
comment on EVMS Elon Musk says that no
country should have electronic voting
machines because they can be hacked
excuse me even non-electronic voting
voting methods can be hacked as we know
very well every system every process can
be hacked nothing is
infallible every government can be
hacked every exam can be hacked every
bureaucracy can be hacked and corrupted
everything can be hacked what are you
talking
about so nothing is infallible what you
need is integrity and the right
processes just because you have paper
ballots doesn't mean that your system is
infallible you can have what what what
do you have ballot stuffing and what not
used to happen you know Mass you take a
bunch of ballots and stamp them all and
then stuff the ballots that is to happen
in the past in various parts of the
world so nothing is invaluable that is
actually a very I would say childish
take on the matter okay that does it uh
uh we are at the end of today's stream
I'm going to end it over here so thank
you so much once again for all your
questions
and I will see you in next week's live
streams so until then then as always
keep asking questions keep raising your
standards keep improving whatever you're
doing and take care I will see you very
soon in next week's live streams bye